Guide to the John Ruskin Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1829-1949; Series I
  - Letters from John Ruskin to Identified Individuals
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Heaton. No place., undated (Box 8)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund, 1997 March 18
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Hewitt. No place., undated (paper watermarked 1859) (Box 8)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Geo[rge] A. Hitchcock. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1874 March (Box 8)
      Bought from David J. Holmes on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1997 July 25
    - Autograph note, signed, to [George] Hogarth. No place., 1859 December 24 (Box 8)
      Bought on the Library Associates Fund, 1934
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Hogarth. No place., [1866] (Box 8)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2001 March 9
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Frederick [Hollyer?]. Coniston., undated (Box 8)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Hollyer. British Hotel., undated (Box 8)
    - 5 autograph letters, signed, to Marcus B. Huish. Lancashire., 1882-1884 (Box 8)
      Bought from George Bayntum on the Plain Fund, 1954 June 16
    - 7 autograph letters, signed, to William Humphreys. Denmark Hill and London., 1855-1856 (Box 8)
      Two of the letters include drafts of replies by William Humphreys.
      Bought on the Robert H. Taylor Fund, 1953
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Hunt. London., 1864 February 10 (Box 8)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Inchbold. Lancashire., 1873 May 30 (Box 9)
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to James Jackson Jarves. London., [1855 May 3], 1855 October 29 (Box 9)
      Bought on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1946
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Canon Jenkins. [Brantwood]., 1888 March 4 (Box 9)
      Bought from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2001 February 26
    - Autograph letter, signed, to George Jones. Herne Hill., 1853 April 18 (Box 9)
      Bought from Jarndyce on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2003 June 30
    - Autograph letter, signed, to George Jones. Boulogne., 1861 July 10 (Box 9)
      Bought from R. Metzdorf on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1960 July 6
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Jowett. Denmark Hill., [1870] April 28 (Box 9)
    - 79 autograph letters, signed, to Henry Jowett. Various places. In a half-box case., 1874-1889 (Box 34 (Oversize))
      Includes catalogue entry.
      Includes autograph letter, signed, from William Gershom Collingwood (1854-1932) to Henry Jowett. Windermere. 1888 August 21.
    - Autograph note, signed with initials, to [Henry] Jowett. No place., 1877 May 27 (Box 9)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Edward Wells Southworth Fund, 1944 June 13
    - 46 autograph letters, signed, to Henry Jowett. Various places., 1882-1889, undated (Box 9)
      Gift of Chauncey B. Tinker, 1941
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Jowett. Coniston., [no year] May 7 (Box 9)
      Bought from Robert F. Metzdorf on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1956 November 29
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to [Henry] Jowett. Oxford, Herne Hill., [no year] May 22, undated (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to C. A. Keary. Brantwood., 1883 February 8 (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1995 September 27
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Coulson Kernahan. Ambleside., 1887 January 4 (Box 9)
      Bought from Arthur Rogers on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1956 September 26
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand Charles Kingsley. Denmark Hill, Camberwell., 1855 March 7 (Box 9)
      Includes a copy photograph of John Ruskin.
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1996 August 19
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand Charles Kingsley. No place., undated (Box 9)
      Accompanied by a carte-de-visite of John Ruskin.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Elizabeth Knox. Denmark Hill., 1865 August 20 (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2000 September 18
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. La Touche. No place., [circa 1870] (Box 9)
      Bought by Herman W. Liebert in England on the Beinecke Endowment Fund, 1965 June
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Austen Henry Layard. No place., [1856] (Box 9)
      Includes an autograph letter, signed, from [Prime Minister Lord] Palmerston to [Austen Henry] Layard, 1865 March 6.
      Bought from Maggs Brothers, Ltd. on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2001 July 18
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Professor Lewis. Denmark Hill., [1867] March 1 (Box 9)
      Bought from Winifred A. Myers (Autographs) Ltd. on the Library Associates Fund, 1980 November 17
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to [Thomas Godd] Lupton. London., 1862 November 14, undated (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Lyon. Denmark Hill., 1866 October 24 (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Philip and Margaret Neufeld Fund of the Yale Library Associates, 1996 February 25
    - Autograph letter, signed, to George MacDonald. Denmark Hill., 1868 June 7 (Box 9)
      Gift of Charles E. Goodspeed, 1946 June 28
    - Autograph letter, signed, to William Mackenzie. Glasgow., 1857 May 26 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Arthur Mackmurdo. London., 1882 February 3 (postmark) (Box 9)
      Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from Arthur Mackmurdo to his niece concerning his recollections of Ruskin, 1932 March 1
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to J. A. Fuller Maitland. No place and Brantwood., 1882 June 28 and 1883 May 1 (Box 9)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Plain Fund, 1943 February 25
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Stacy Marks. No place., [circa 1876 January 16] (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2002 September 5
    - Typed copies of 10 letters to Frederic W. Maynard. Various places., 1873-1874 (Box 9)
      Gift of Andrew Block, 1939
      Accompanied by a typed letter, signed, from Andrew Block to Chauncey B. Tinker, 1939 December 20
    - 12 autograph letters, signed, to John F. Moss. Various places., 1882-1883 (Box 9)
      Bought from B. H. Blackwell on the Plain Fund, 1954 June 16
      Accompanied by a letter from Ruskin to Mr. M. Hunter, Mayor of Sheffield, enclosing a signed statement by Ruskin concerning the museum, 1883 December 2-3.
    - 2 autograph letters, signed with initials, to [Lady Mount-Temple]. Denmark Hill., 1870 August 5, undated (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Fairfax Murray. London., 1882 February 23 (Box 9)
      Includes a carte-de-visite of Ruskin by Elliot & Fry.
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Sir John [Naesmyth]. Denmark Hill and no place., 1857 April 11 and 1859 (watermark) (Box 9)
      Gift of Henry C. Hutchins, 1959 December
      First letter includes envelope.
    - 21 autograph letters, signed, to Sir John and Lady Naesmyth. Various places., 1861-1873 (Box 9)
      Gift of Henry C. Hutchins, 1957
      Includes 2 wrappers and 6 envelopes.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Newton. No place., undated (Box 9)
      Bought from David J. Holmes on the Robert H. Taylor Fund, 1998 April 15
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Nichol. Herne Hill., 1880 November 26 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Nicholls. Denmark Hill., [no year] March 3 (Box 9)
      Gift of Henry C. Hutchins, 1963
    - 18 autograph letters, signed, to Edward B. Nicholson. Various places., 1875-1881 (Box 9)
      Bought from Maggs Brothers Ltd. on the Library Associates Fund, 1950 February 7
    - 4 autograph letters, signed, to Charlotte E. Noyes. London., 1861-1865 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Nockold. No place., 1883 June 4 (Box 9)
      Bought from Charles Hamilton on the Francis O. Matthiessen Fund, 1957 March 25
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Oddie. Denmark Hill., [no year] October 10 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Langston Oldham. Denmark Hill., 1870 September 5 (Box 9)
    - Typed copies of 11 letters to William Roscoe Osler, and 1 typed copy of a letter to T. Smith Osler. Coniston, Oxford., 1873-1895 (Box 9)
      Accompanied by a typed letter, signed, from Andrew Block to Chauncey B. Tinker describing the original letters, 1940 November 21.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Panhurst. Amiens., 1876 October 26 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Panhurst. Lancashire., [no year] June 27 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Paule. Denmark Hill., 1866 November 28 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Peyton. Denmark Hill., 1850 October 14 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Basil M[ontagu] Pickering. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1877 July 20 (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1997 September 25
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand Charles Plummer. Corpus Christi College, Oxford., [no year] June 4 (Box 9)
    - 8 autograph letters, signed, to Miss Poyser. Various places., 1848-1858 (Box 9)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [Samuel] Prout. Folkestone., [1847] December 2 (Box 9)
      Bought from Driscoll on the Francis O. Matthiessen Fund, 1962 April 3
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Rashburr. Herne Hill., 1882 February 7 (Box 9)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Starling W. Childs Library Fund
    - 21 autograph letters, signed, and 4 autograph letters with the signatures cut off, to Miss [Harriette] Rigbye. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1878-1884 (Box 9)
      Letters contain manuscript notes by Miss Rigbye in the margins.
      Accompanied by an autograph letter to "Dearest Violet" signed "F." concerning the letters. Oban [Scotland], [no year] April 23.
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Library Associates Fund, 1952
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Riley. Coniston, Lancashire., 1878 December 5 (Box 9)
      Bought from R. F. Metzdorf on the Francis O. Matthiessen Fund, 1957 July 9
    - 11 autograph letters, signed, to H. S. Roberts. Royal Kent Hotel, Sandgate., 1887-1888, undated (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1995 May 15
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Col[onel] H. C. Robertson. Denmark Hill., 1865 December 6 (Box 9)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1996 November 22
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [Dante Gabriel] R[ossetti]? Windsor., [1855?] April 14 (Box 9)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Library Associates Fund, 1939 April 5
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [William Michael] Rossetti. No place., 1857 February 5 (Box 9)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Childs Fund, 1961
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Edmund Routledge. Denmark Hill., [no year] October 18 (Box 9)
      Bought on the Plain Fund, 1942
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Dr. E. Rushmore, possibly in Ruskin's hand. No place., undated (Box 9)
      Transferred from the Shreve C. Badger Collection in memory of Steven Vincent Benet in the Yale Memorabilia Room, 1945
    - Letter, signed, to John James Ruskin in verse. No place., 1836 March 31 (Box 9)
    - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Margaret Cox Ruskin. Keswick, Coniston., 1867 July 19, 1871 September 13, undated (Box 9)
      Includes 1 envelope.
      Includes a photograph of Ruskin, mounted with his signature.
      Includes photocopy of catalogue entry.
      Bought from Winifred A. Myers (Autographs) Ltd. on the Library Associates Fund, 2003 June 30
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Ryland. Herne Hill., 1883 May 15 (Box 9)
      Gift of Philip Neufeld
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Saddler. Coniston., 1873 January 27 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Ed. Salmons. Vevey., [no year] July 17 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1995 November 1
    - 3 autograph letters, signed, to W. A. Saunders. Brantwood, Broadlands, Oxford., 1873 December 23, 1875 January 5, 1875 December 11 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to J. Scott. No place., [1857] (Box 10)
      Bought on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1957
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Scudamore. Denmark Hill., [1887] (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Joan Ruskin Severn. No place., 1887 November 4 (Box 10)
      Gift of Henry C. Hutchins, 1963 December
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Joseph Severn. No place., [before 1860?] (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Walter Severn. No place., undated (Box 10)
      On the verso is an autograph letter, signed, from Severn to "Joyce", 1877 January 15.
    - 5 autograph letters, signed, to Reverand William Sharman. Various places., 1875 September 3-December 14 (Box 10)
      Accompanied by a draft of a letter by Rev. Sharman to Ruskin, [1875] November 18.
      Gift of Marshall Bartholomew, 1959 June
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Simon. Boulogne., [no year] June 28 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Jane Simpson. Denmark Hill., 1860 November 26 (Box 10)
      Bought from Schroder on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1955 August 15
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Catherine [Agnew] Simson. London., 1867 June 5 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Alfred Slocombe. London., 1880 April 13 (Box 10)
    - 5 autograph letters, signed, and 3 autograph letters with signatures removed, to James Smetham. Various places., 1859-1871, undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [James] Smetham. No place., [circa 1862] (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to B. Woodd Smith. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1880 July 8 (Box 10)
      Includes a postcard of John Ruskin at Brantwood, Abraham's Series, No. 833, Keswick, [1885 July 18]
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [J. C. L.?] Sparkes. Denmark Hill., undated (Box 10)
      Bought from John Heise Autograph Shop on the Library Associates Fund, 1938 December 17
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Sparkes. Denmark Hill., 1867 November 25 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Sparkes. Oxford., 1876 February 4 (Box 10)
      Gift of Bernard Knollenberg, 1946
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Spooner. Denmark Hill., undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Stanley. No place., undated (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2004 March 30
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Arthur Stannard. Sandgate., 1888 February 1, 1888 March 2 (Box 10)
    - 17 autograph letters, signed, to Mrs. Arthur Stannard. Sandgate., 1887 November 6-1888 May 22, undated (Box 10)
      Includes catalogue description.
      Includes 8 envelopes.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Stewart. [Herne Hill]., [1882 February 24] (Box 10)
    - Reproduction of an autograph letter, signed, to William Stillman. No place., 1856 (postmark) (Box 10)
      Includes a typed transcript of the letter.
      Gift of Alfred E. Richards (The Library Associates)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to W. J. Stillman. [London], [1861 December 31] (Box 10)
      Bought from Morton on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1960 November 16
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Suckling. Sandgate, 2 Devonshire Terrace., 1888 March 24 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Talbot. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1887 February 8 (Box 10)
    - 50 autograph letters, signed, to Richard Talling. Various places., 1865-1873 (Box 10)
      Includes 9 envelopes.
      Bought from Seven Gables Bookshop on the McGuire Fund, 1958 January 31
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Edward L. Tarbuck. Denmark Hill, Tunbridge Wells., 1854 May 11, undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mona M. Tate. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1887 March 10 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund, 2004 September 14
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Joseph Taylor. Denmark Hill., 1863 July 22 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Tom Taylor. London., undated (Box 10)
      Bought from Hamill and Barker on the Starling W. Childs Library Fund, 1963 July 17
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Dora Thomas. Sheffield., 1880 February 16 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Thorn. Denmark Hill., 1866 November 11 (Box 10)
      Bought from Carnegie Book Shop on the McGuire Fund, 1960 September 29
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Sir John Salusbury Trelawny. Denmark Hill., 1860 March 18 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Trevelyan [Mrs. Sir Walter Trevelyan]. [London]., undated (Box 10)
      Accompanied by a carte-de-visite of Ruskin by Elliott & Fry.
      Bought from Main Street Fine Books & Manuscripts, Ltd. on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1997 February 5
    - Autograph note, signed, to Messieurs Trubner & Co. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1878 July 7 (Box 10)
      Bought from C. A. Stonehill on the Starling W. Childs Library Fund, 1958 October 13
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [Sir] Alfred [Edward] Turner. Coniston., 1886 February 24 (Box 10)
    - 14 autograph letters, signed, to members of the Tylor family. Various places., 1866-1872, undated (Box 10)
      Includes typed copies of some letters.
      Gift of Herman W. Liebert, 1952
    - 22 autograph letters, signed, and 1 autograph letter, to members of the Tylor family. Various places., 1873-1875 December 26 (Box 10)
    - 11 autograph letters, signed, to members of the Tylor family. Various places., 1876 March 27-1886 January 19 (Box 10)
      Includes manuscript copies of 3 letters to Delamere Tylor.
      Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from John Ruskin to Mrs. Severn. Broadlands. [1875 November or December].
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand R. S[t.] J[ohn] Tyrrwhitt. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1879 September 14 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2002 January 31
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [David?] Urquhart. Denmark Hill., undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Wade. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., [no year] March 22 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to E[dward] Walford. Denmark Hill., 1866 January 15 (Box 10)
      Bought from John Wilson on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1999 April 19
    - Autograph letter, signed, to W. H. Wallis. London., 1869 March 10 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to J. A. Walls. Blair Athol., [no year] August 21 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1997 July 25
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [Edward Matthew] Ward. Denmark Hill., [1871] May 19 (Box 10)
      Gift from the estate of Katherine Dreier, 1952 November
    - Autograph letter, signed, to William Ward. Canterbury., 1879 September 26-27 (Box 10)
      Accompanied by a postcard portrait of John Ruskin.
      Bought from John Wilson on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2003 March 10
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Tho[ma]s Warsop. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1886 October 7 (Box 10)
      Accompanied by the typescript of a poem, "Kind Words Can Never Die," by Mabel Usher, with manuscript annotations.
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund, 2002 January 31
    - Autograph letter, signed, to G. F. West. Lancashire., 1886 June 2 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. White. No place., undated (Box 10)
      Bought from Parke-Bernet Galleries on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1958 January 28
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [William] Hale White. No place., undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Wilkins. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1878 February 4 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1999 May 10
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Wilkins. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1881 November 14 (Box 10)
    - 17 autograph letters, signed, to C. F. Williams. Various places., 1853-1859 (Box 10)
      Accompanied by a manuscript copy of the letter from 1857 May 24 in an unidentified hand.
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to William Smith Williams. Denmark Hill, no place., 1870 December 19, undated (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to W. Smith Williams. Denmark Hill., [no year] June 24 (Box 10)
      Gift of Henry C. Hutchins, 1959
    - Autograph letter, signed, to A. J. Woodhouse. Lancashire., 1873 February 18 (Box 10)
      Bought from W. R. Benjamin on the Plain Fund, 1953 June 20
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Woods. Denmark Hill., 1859 December 3 (Box 10)
      Bought from John Heise Autograph Shop on the Edward Wells Southworth Fund, 1940 October 5
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Woodward. Keswick., 1867 July 4 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Woodward. Denmark Hill., 1868 December 2 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [Thomas] Woolner. No place., undated (Box 10)
      Bought from Maggs Brothers Ltd. on the Louis Mayer Rabinowitz Memorial Fund, 1990 August 7
    - Autograph letter, signed, to G. W. Wright of the Glastonbury Literary Institute. Denmark Hill., 1865 August 15 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre as a bequest of Harry T. Mercer, Yale 1924, and Dorothy N. Mercer, for use of the Tinker Library, 1995 February 10.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [G. W. Wright of the Glastonbury Literary Institute]. Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1880 June 23 (Box 10)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1995 July 24
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Major C. Wyndham. No place., [no year] May 23 (Box 10)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Frederick Young. Denmark Hill., 1870 January 20 (Box 10)
  - Letters from John Ruskin to Individuals identified only by First Name or Title
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "My dear Alice." Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1879 August 14 (Box 11)
      Bought from David J. Holmes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund, 1990 September 14
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dearest Caloforte." Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1887 June 27 (Box 11)
      William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1956. Francis O. Matthiessen Fund, 1957.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dearest Doctor." No place., [1880] November 5 (Box 11)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Darling Donnie." Oxford., undated (Box 11)
      Gift of an anonymous donor, 1968 August 6
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "My dear Editor." Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1886 January 11 (Box 11)
      Bought from Maggs Brothers Ltd. on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 1996 December 3
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "My dear Ethel." Venice., 1877 Epiphany [January 12] (Box 11)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Fidos." Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1884 January 5 (Box 11)
      Bought from Clive Farahar and Sophie Dupre on the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Prize Fund, 2005 May 5
    - Autograph letter, signed with initials, to "Darling Geraldine." No place., 1884 January 4 (Box 11)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Gertrude." No place., 1888 February 15 (Box 11)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Gordan." Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire., 1880 April 29 (Box 11)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Gordan." No place., undated (Box 11)